MATTHEW HARDWICK matthardwick@gmail.com 559-362-2408

704 E. Clinton Ave., Fresno, CA, 93704

www.github.com/matthardwick - www.linkedin.com/in/mattdhardwick

Skills Summary

I am a Front-End Web Developer, Licensed health insurance agent as well as a long time customer service expert.

I've helped businesses focus on their product/service instead of being distracted by the volatile nature of the insurance industry. I have held a customer-interacting job since I was in high-school and have learned how to handle virtually any situation on the spot. I also love to build websites and web applications.

When I'm not working or trying to learn something new, you can find me playing with my dog or obsessing over mechanical keyboards.

Education

Hanford West High School (Diploma - 2004)

Udacity Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree

Completed in October 2016, you can view all of my course projects on my GitHub page.

Work Experience

DerManouel Insurance Group

Account Manager / April 2013 to September 2016

Licensed Insurance Agent in California for Life and Health. Managing a dedicated book of business, responsible for maintenance of the account as well as marketing from beginning to end. In the three years I spent with people who had a minimum of 15 years experience I was able to become the Account Manager handling one of the highest amount of clients in company revenue, second only to the department manager. Millions of dollars of commission and thousands of client's employees were my responsibility.

In addition to everyday duties of employee benefits account management, I built tools and applications that massively improved my department's efficiency as well as custom applications for clients to better help their employees make critical life decisions regarding their (and their family's) healthcare.

Aetna Inc.

Customer Service Representative / January 2008 to April 2013

- Taking calls from an inbound queue from members, providers, plan sponsors, and brokers.
- Assigned to the "mentor queue," taking calls from other customer service representatives and handling supervisor requests.
- Monitoring the "Fresno Small Group Mailbox," an email box designed to answer questions from brokers, general agents, and Sales Executives regarding escalated claim and enrollment issues.
- Regional Business Sales Support Appreciation Award for 2012. Recognized for performing excellent service and collaborative efforts to Aetna's Sales team.

Alpha Designs

Graphics Designer / April 2004 to June 2006

- Managed orders from customers in person and over the phone
- Developed graphics for silk-screen, embroidery, signs, and print.
- Installed signs and vinyl graphics as well as sand blasting.

Personal Projects

Fullstack Project - Multi-User Blog

https://mhardwick-blog-project.appspot.com - https://github.com/matthardwick/fullstack-blog

Using python, jijna2 templates and polymer components, created a multi-user blog platform on Google's App Engine

Personal Portfolio Page

http://mattdhardwick.com/portfolio

Developed a personal portfolio page using HTML, CSS, and the Bootstrap framework. The page is fully responsive and works on mobile, tablet, and desktop browsers.

Interactive Resume

https://github.com/matthardwick/frontend-resume

Using jQuery, developed an interactive resume application that reads all data from a JSON file and dynamically modifies the DOM.

Google Maps API Project

https://github.com/matthardwick/maps-api-project

A single-page web application, built using the Knockout framework, that displays a Google Map of an area and various points of interest. Users can search all included landmarks and, when selected, additional information about a landmark is presented from the FourSquare API.

Website Optimization Project

https://github.com/matthardwick/frontend-nanodegree-mobile-portfolio

Two separate projects, one to optimize an inefficient website to a pagespeed insights score above 90 for mobile and desktop, and another to fix the critical rendering path and remove the jank causing it to run below 60 frames per second.

Where the Garden Grows Preschool

https://github.com/matthardwick/wtgg

Hosted on digital ocean ubuntu 14.04, set up the webserver/server block. Running Grav CMS for the business owner to maintain. I volunteered my time/hosting cost, free website for them, free practice for me.